Evan Sagge

Web Applications Developer Washington DC Metro Area +1.813.505.7366 http://evansagge.com evansagge@gmail.com

I am a software developer with a focus on web applications development, with years of experience in various languages such as Ruby, Java, PHP and C/C++. I specialize in writing web applications, using mostly Ruby on Rails and Rack-based frameworks. I also write code in Javascript/Coffeescript and designing clean and simple HTML5/CSS3-compliant web UIs.

I am heavily influenced with agile development practices, mostly from Scrum, REST-ful web development, test-driven development, and later on behavior-driven development, ensuring that the desired software behavior are properly identified from a practical standpoint and at the same time focusing on delivering simple, efficient, and usable software.

In my free time, I enjoy playing soccer, hiking, running, biking, and traveling to new places.

I also keep a repository of personal and open-source projects on my Github page: http://github.com/evansagge.

Specializations

Ruby, Ruby on Rails 3.x/2.x, MongoDB, NoSQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Javascript, Coffeescript, jQuery, CSS

Professional Experience

Ruby on Rails Consultant at **Gannett** (http://gannett.com) - 2012

- Implemented Salesforce CRM backend requirements using Apex
- Developed Visualforce pages for Salesforce CRM
- Worked on Salesforce CRM integration projects using Ruby on Rails
- Relevant Technologies: Salesforce CRM, Apex, Java, Visualforce, Ruby, Ruby on Rails 3.x, CSS3, HTML5, Javascript, jQuery, Git, Mercurial, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Linux, Agile methods

Associate, Software Developer at **iLab Solutions** (http://ilabsolutions.com) - Aug 2011 to Jun 2012

- Developed and maintained new and existing products and features for in-house web applications using Ruby on Rails and Javascript/Coffeescript
- Ported existing applications from using Prototype to jQuery
- Relevant Technologies: Ruby, Ruby on Rails 2.x, Ruby on Rails 3.2, Javascript, jQuery, Prototype, Coffeescript, CSS3, HTML5, Twitter Bootstrap, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Git, Linux, Haml, Slim, SCSS/SASS, Sunspot, Solr, Agile methods, Continuous Integration

Technical Lead at Infinite.ly (http://infinite.ly) - Jan 2010 to Jun 2012

- Developed Ruby on Rails 3 web applications using MongoDB and back-ground processes using Resque and Redis
- Implemented search and indexing capabilities using ElasticSearch
- Designed interfaces to connect with external web-based APIs such as Facebook Graph, Twitter, Google Data, and Flickr APIs to obtain social media data
- Managed remote server infrastructure on Linux instances using Nginx, Unicorn, Bluepill, Monit and Newrelic
- Relevant Technogies: Ruby, Ruby on Rails 3.x, Rack, Javascript, Coffeescript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Linux, Nginx, Unicorn, Monit, NewRelic, REST, APIs, ElasticSearch, MongoDB, Redis, Haml, Slim, SCSS/SASS, Git, Agile methods, RSpec, Cucumber, Continuous Integration

Consultant Web Developer (Part-Time) at **Deal Grocer** (http://dealgrocer.com)- Sept 2011 to Jan 2012

- Developed additional features for main web application using Cuba (a Rack-based web framework) and Ohm (Redis-based ORM)
- Relevant Technologies: Ruby, Rack, Cuba, Ohm, Redis, CSS3, HTML5, Haml, SCSS/SASS, Javascript, jQuery, Git, Slim, Extreme Programming, Continuous Integration

Software Engineer at Exist Global (http://exist.com) - Oct 2008 to Jan 2010

 Implemented and maintained web and mobile applications for various cli-ents, most of which are developed using Ruby on Rails technologies.

- Developed new features and enhanced existing functionalities for the TotSpot social networking web site using Facebook's OpenStream API and Twitter's OAuth API
- Developed a web-based photo-management application using Ruby on Rails 2.3.x and Facebook REST API
- Developed iPhone application to render photos as cartoonized images
- Relevant Technologies: Ruby, Ruby on Rails 2.x/3.x, Rack, Javascript, Coffeescript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, SASS, LESS, Linux, Nginx, APIs, REST, Agile methods, iOS, Objective C, SVN, Git, RSpec, Cucumber

Web Developer at **Syndeo Media** (http://syndeomedia.com) - Oct 2007 to Oct 2008

- Implemented new features and enhanced existing functionalities for client-based projects using Ruby on Rails
- Relevant Technologies: Ruby, Ruby on Rails 1.x/2.x, Javascript, Prototype, jQuery, HTML, CSS, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, APIs, REST, Agile methods, SVN, Git, RSpec, Test::Unit

Software Developer at **Solegy** - May 2006 to Oct 2007

- Developed and maintained new and existing software solutions using a mix of C++,
 Java (J2SE and J2EE) and Ruby coding languages
- Relevant Technologies: C++, Java, Ruby, DTrace, Spring MVC, Hibernate, Parlay, SOAP, MysSQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle SQL, Solaris, CVS, SVN, JUnit

Part-Time Instructor at **Ateneo de Manila University** - Jun 2005 to Nov 2005

Software Design Engineer at **Blue Chip Designs** (http://bcdph.com) - Mar 2005 to May 2006

- Developed software solutions (drivers, firmware, desktop applications) for thermal printer devices, point-of-sales systems using C/C++ and OLE, Ac-tiveX, COM, MFC frameworks
- Relevant Technologies: C, C++, Microsoft Visual Studio, MFC, OLE, ActiveX, Ruby, PHP, HTML, CSS, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MS SQL Server, CVS

Freelance Work

Training Payback (http://trainingpayback.com) - 2007 to 2008

 Developed new features and enhance existing functionalities using Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL

Babyland (http://babyland.com.ph) - 2006

Designed and developed the original website using CakePHP and MySQL

Schema Konsult (http://schemakonsult.com) - 2007

Designed and developed the website using PHP and MySQL

Open Source Projects

Mongoid-RSpec (https://github.com/evansagge/mongoid-rspec)

- RSpec plugin to provide matchers for the Mongoid ORM
- primary developer

Flickr-OAuth (https://github.com/evansagge/flickr_oauth)

- simple Ruby library for connecting to the Flickr API
- primary developer

Numeric Array (https://github.com/evansagge/numeric_array)

- Ruby library extending Array objects to provide methods for mathematical and statistical calculations
- primary developer

CakePHP (http://cakephp.org)

- PHP-based web development framework, similar to Ruby on Rails for Ruby
- contributor from 2005-2007

Education

- Ateneo de Manila University, Philippines B.S. Computer Engineering, 2000 2005
- Ateneo de Manila University, Philippines B.S. Physics, 2000 2004

References

Available upon request